<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: socks | What is the name of this Blog?]]></title>
  <link href="https://lalyos.github.io/blog/categories/socks/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://lalyos.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-18T22:34:13+01:00</updated>
  <id>https://lalyos.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[lalyos]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Access docker containers via internal ip]]></title>
    <link href="https://lalyos.github.io/blog/2013/10/06/access-docker-containers-via-internal-ip/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-06T09:34:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>https://lalyos.github.io/blog/2013/10/06/access-docker-containers-via-internal-ip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whenn you run a lot of containers inside of a docker host, you can get lost of the forwarded ports. Let's say you have 3 instances all exposing 3 ports: 22, 80 and 443. Docker will automatically assign 'random' port numbers like:</p>

<p><code>
ID            ...  PORTS
656eb7831dda  ...  49162-&gt;22, 49163-&gt;80, 49164-&gt;443   
ff2141eb218d  ...  49159-&gt;22, 49160-&gt;80, 49161-&gt;443   
54b9dfd5400c  ...  49156-&gt;22, 49157-&gt;80, 49158-&gt;443   
</code></p>

<p>Now its hard to remember all those ports, and is confusing that if you want to ssh into the first one, you use <code>ssh root@docker -p 49162</code> and in the browser you would use: <code>http://docker:49163</code>.</p>

<p>There is an even bigger problem with random ports. Wehn your <strong>http</strong> server sometimes redirects you to <strong>https</strong>, you need the standard port numbers. The webserver running inside of a docker container, will redirect you to port <strong>443</strong> which will not be correct port (49164 in our case)</p>

<p>So it would be much natural for the docker instances to use their ip address, with <em>straight</em> port numbers. But those ip addresses are only valid inside of the docker host. How to do the magic?</p>

<h2>SSH is yor best friend</h2>

<p>There is complete SOCKS proxy hidden indide of ssh. To get it alive you just have to toss a <code>-D 1099</code> parameter, and boom, it will listen on your localhost's 1099 port and act as a proxy. So here is a how you create an ssh based <em>tunnel</em> :</p>

<p><code>
ssh -qTfN2 -D 1099 docker
</code></p>

<p>For the curious the parameter meanings:</p>

<ul>
<li>q :- be very quite</li>
<li>T :- Do not allocate a pseudo tty</li>
<li>f :- move the ssh process to background</li>
<li>N :- Do not execute remote command.</li>
<li>2 :- Forces ssh to try protocol version 2 only.</li>
</ul>


<h2>docker internal IPs</h2>

<p>How can you get the internal ip of a container? You can get all the dirty details by: <code>sudo docker inspect XXXXX</code>. For the moment the only interresting this is the IP addresses. So the oneliner is:</p>

<p><code>
for i in $(sudo docker ps -q); do sudo docker inspect $i| grep IPA; done
</code></p>

<p>it will create the following list:</p>

<p>```</p>

<pre><code>    "IPAddress": "172.17.0.12",
    "IPAddress": "172.17.0.11",
    "IPAddress": "172.17.0.10",
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<h2>SOCKS proxy</h2>

<p>Now all the programs which can use a SOCKS proxy can access the docker containers. For example let's poke the first containers webserver with <code>curl</code></p>

<p><code>
curl --proxy socks5h://localhost:1099  172.17.0.10
</code></p>

<p>for a java process ypu can specify it by system properties: <code>-DsocksProxyHost=127.0.0.1 -DsocksProxyPort=1099</code></p>

<h2>SOCKS proxy for the browser</h2>

<p>You have probably already uses an http proxy in your browser. In that case <strong>all trafic</strong> goes throught the http proxy. For our usecase what we wan is:</p>

<ul>
<li>accessing docker containers via <strong>SOCKS proxy</strong></li>
<li>all other shoud be accessed <strong>directly</strong></li>
</ul>


<p>Luckily thus problem is already solved by the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proxy_auto-config">Proxy auto-config</a> or shortly PAC. Its a JavaScript function which returns with the connection type: PROXY/SOCKS/DIRECT. See the sample below:</p>

<p>```
function FindProxyForURL(url, host) {</p>

<pre><code>    // URLs within this network are accessed through
    // socks proxy provided by ssh -D
    if (isInNet(host, "172.17.0.0", "255.255.0.0"))
    {
            return "SOCKS 127.0.0.1:1099";
    }

    return "DIRECT";
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<h2>SSH doesn't need a SOCKS proxy</h2>

<p>We use ssh to create a SOCKS proxy, which can be used by other programs java/browser/curl and so on. But ssh is clever enough that if there is no SOCKS proxy opened, it can create it on demand:</p>

<p><code>
ssh -o ProxyCommand='ssh user@10.253.129.151 nc %h %p' user@targetsshserver.example.com
</code></p>

<p>This tells ssh that instead of connecting directly to targetsshserver.example.com's port 22, use a <strong>ProxyCommand</strong> to create the connection.</p>

<p>In this case the command itself is an ssh: <code>ssh user@docker nc %h %p</code> which means start a <strong>NetCat</strong> (nc host port) via ssh.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
