<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mac | What is the name of this Blog?]]></title>
  <link href="https://lalyos.github.io/blog/categories/mac/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://lalyos.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-18T22:34:13+01:00</updated>
  <id>https://lalyos.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[lalyos]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fix a broken mac terminal]]></title>
    <link href="https://lalyos.github.io/blog/2014/02/28/fix-a-broken-mac-terminal/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-28T14:32:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://lalyos.github.io/blog/2014/02/28/fix-a-broken-mac-terminal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes my <code>Terminal</code> gets broken by either displaying binary files, or sometimes caused by a broken ssh connection.</p>

<p>You can fix it by copy pasting the following line:</p>

<p>```
tput init
tput reset
reset</p>

<p><code>``
You might not see the charaters even after pasted to the terminal, but keep on press</code>ENTER`, and suddenly your terminal is back to normal.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Install sshpass on mac]]></title>
    <link href="https://lalyos.github.io/blog/2013/09/30/install-sshpass-on-mac/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-30T14:07:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>https://lalyos.github.io/blog/2013/09/30/install-sshpass-on-mac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm experimenting with <a href="http://www.ansibleworks.com/">ansibe</a>, an awesome IT orchestration engine. It deservse its own blog entry, but in short: <strong>It's an alternative of puppet and chef, but its much easier to learn</strong>, and dowsn't require any client side agent installation.</p>

<h2>passwordless ssh</h2>

<p>Its higly recommended to use public key authentication, but sometimes you have to deal with passwords. Let's say a fresh virtual environment is always created with a default password.</p>

<p>When I tried to call ansible with <strong>-k</strong> password, meaning ask for password, i faced the following message:</p>

<p><code>
to use the 'ssh' connection type with passwords, you must install the sshpass program
</code></p>

<h2>installing sshpass</h2>

<p>Installing sshpass on linux is as easy as calling <em>apt-get</em> or <em>yum</em>, whatever package manager its using. Unfortunately <strong>homebrwe</strong>, my favourite package manager for mac doesn't supports this package officially.</p>

<p>Actually it was created, but the team refused to take <a href="https://github.com/mxcl/homebrew/pull/9577">it</a> as its a bad practice to put passwords into scripts.</p>

<p>However there is an unofficial brew package:</p>

<p><code>
brew install https://raw.github.com/eugeneoden/homebrew/eca9de1/Library/Formula/sshpass.rb
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
