<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: docker | What is the name of this Blog?]]></title>
  <link href="http://lalyos.github.com/blog/categories/docker/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lalyos.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-24T17:21:25+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://lalyos.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[lalyos]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[fixing startup on docker]]></title>
    <link href="http://lalyos.github.com/blog/2013/10/01/fixing-startup-on-docker/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-01T15:31:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lalyos.github.com/blog/2013/10/01/fixing-startup-on-docker</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When working in <a href="http://www.docker.io/">docker</a> container, you need to start services differently. Let's say you want to start <strong>mysql</strong>. You have 3 choices:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>mysqld_safe &amp;</code> which is a quick and dirty solution but its not idempotent.</li>
<li><code>/etc/init.d/mysql restart</code> its the <em>old school</em> way</li>
<li><code>service mysql start</code> that's the <em>new school</em> way</li>
</ul>


<p>Normally you would prefer the 3. option <code>service mysql start</code> but it needs <em>upstart</em> running which is normally the <strong>/sbin/init</strong> process with the special <strong>pid</strong> of 1.</p>

<p>Unfortunately inside of a docker instance the special <strong>1 pid</strong> is rserved for the command started by docker. In most case its either <strong>/bin/bash</strong>, or <strong>sshd</strong>, ot whatever service you are running in the container.</p>

<p>when you try to start mysql with  then you will most probably face the following message:</p>

<p><code>
 Failed to connect to socket /com/ubuntu/upstart: Connection refused
</code></p>

<p>thats because upstart is not running, or phrasing differently: <strong>1 pid</strong> is not <strong>/sbin/init</strong></p>

<h2>upstart workaround</h2>

<p>There is a workaround for supressing this messages:</p>

<p><code>
dpkg-divert --local --rename --add /sbin/initctl
ln -s /bin/true /sbin/initctl
</code></p>

<p>Of course you stil can't use <code>service mysql start</code>, but at least you wont get those error messages.</p>

<h2>related issues / pull-reqs</h2>

<p>I can see that the docker issues/pull requests are disscussing it. But im still not sure the proper way to go. But here are the references:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/dotcloud/docker/issues/223">issue 223</a>: the original <strong>Run /sbin/init</strong> issue</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/dotcloud/docker/issues/1024">issue 1024</a>: the <strong>Container cannot connect to Upstart</strong> issue where i found the workaround</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/dotcloud/docker/issues/1311">issue 1311</a> : <strong>Production-ready process monitoring</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/dotcloud/docker/pull/898">pull-req 898</a>: Inject dockerinit at /.dockerinit instead of overwriting /sbin/init</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/dotcloud/docker/pull/1209">pull-req 1209</a>: Upstart improvements</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/dotcloud/docker/pull/1883">pull-req 1883</a>:  /usr/sbin/policy-rc.d  is added since the vast majority of docker users are surprised when they apt-get install or apt-get upgrade and services fail to start and that sometimes makes the install fail</li>
</ul>


<h2>update</h2>

<p>I just read the docker integration into <code>supervisor</code>-s () is <a href="http://blog.docker.io/2013/08/websockets-dockerfile-upgrade-better-registry-support-expert-mode-and-more/#better_integration_with_process_supervisors">planned</a> for the upcomming 0.7 version</p>

<blockquote><p>For docker to be fully usable in production, it needs to cleanly integrate with the host machine’s process supervisor of choice. Whether it’s sysV-init, upstart, systemd, runit or supervisord, we want to make sure docker plays nice with your existing system. This will be a major focus of the 0.7 release.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
