<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ansible | What is the name of this Blog?]]></title>
  <link href="http://lalyos.github.com/blog/categories/ansible/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lalyos.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-24T17:21:25+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://lalyos.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[lalyos]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[debug ansible]]></title>
    <link href="http://lalyos.github.com/blog/2013/10/01/debug-ansible/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-01T16:51:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lalyos.github.com/blog/2013/10/01/debug-ansible</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you reaaly want to see the ctual scripts ansible is running use the  <code>ANSIBLE_KEEP_REMOTE_FILES=1</code> to prevent ansible from deleting remote files.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>tl;dr</h2>

<p><a href="http://www.ansibleworks.com/">Ansible</a> is the new kid in the <em>Configuration Management</em> / <em>Application Deployment</em> / <em>Continuous Delivery</em> field. Its much easier to learn than puppet/chef and it using <strong>yaml</strong> for describing playbooks.</p>

<p>Sometimes yo run into trouble when using ansible and want to get more detailed output for debugging the issue. Of course there is the <code>-v</code> option which can be even more verbose with <code>-vvv</code>.</p>

<h2>How ansible works</h2>

<p>Ansible is well known for its unique feature of: <strong>no agent needed</strong>. Actually it does need something on the orchestrated node, namely pytho. But its true that in most modern *nix its already provided.</p>

<p>So How does ansible works behinde the sceenes:</p>

<ul>
<li>you desribe your <strong>playbook</strong> in a YAML file</li>
<li>ansible generates a python script</li>
<li>copies it to the target node via ssh</li>
<li>runs the python script</li>
<li>collects the output/return codes</li>
<li>deletes all the temporary scriptes/files from the remote host.</li>
</ul>


<p>If you want to avoid the last step you can use the mentioned environment variable as:</p>

<p><code>
ANSIBLE_KEEP_REMOTE_FILES=1  ansible -vvvv host -m shell -a 'hstname'
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Install sshpass on mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://lalyos.github.com/blog/2013/09/30/install-sshpass-on-mac/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-30T14:07:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lalyos.github.com/blog/2013/09/30/install-sshpass-on-mac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm experimenting with <a href="http://www.ansibleworks.com/">ansibe</a>, an awesome IT orchestration engine. It deservse its own blog entry, but in short: <strong>It's an alternative of puppet and chef, but its much easier to learn</strong>, and dowsn't require any client side agent installation.</p>

<h2>passwordless ssh</h2>

<p>Its higly recommended to use public key authentication, but sometimes you have to deal with passwords. Let's say a fresh virtual environment is always created with a default password.</p>

<p>When I tried to call ansible with <strong>-k</strong> password, meaning ask for password, i faced the following message:</p>

<p><code>
to use the 'ssh' connection type with passwords, you must install the sshpass program
</code></p>

<h2>installing sshpass</h2>

<p>Installing sshpass on linux is as easy as calling <em>apt-get</em> or <em>yum</em>, whatever package manager its using. Unfortunately <strong>homebrwe</strong>, my favourite package manager for mac doesn't supports this package officially.</p>

<p>Actually it was created, but the team refused to take <a href="https://github.com/mxcl/homebrew/pull/9577">it</a> as its a bad practice to put passwords into scripts.</p>

<p>However there is an unofficial brew package:</p>

<p><code>
brew install https://raw.github.com/eugeneoden/homebrew/eca9de1/Library/Formula/sshpass.rb
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
